Hey English learners, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. Today
I want to talk about learning English
while exercising.
Learning English while you work out or
walk or hike or run, etc.
I think that this is a great topic to
talk about because it will help you
learn English and also be healthy. And
this is actually my favorite way to
practice languages and study languages.
I love combining
these two things, exercise and language
learning. It helps me be healthier and
it helps me find more time to do my
language learning. So, in this video,
I'm gonna talk about why and how to
combine your language learning and your
exercise. And by the way, if you want my
help to understand native English
speakers when they speak fast, and if
you want my training to help you
pronounce words and phrases more like a
native English speaker, then click on
the link below in the description to get
my training. Okay, let's talk about why
you should learn English while
exercising. So, first of all, you should
be active. You should do exercise,
walk or uh ride a bike,
hike, maybe exercise at the gym. You
should be active. You should exercise
and do things. It's healthy for you. Of
course, we need this. We need to
exercise. We need to uh work our
muscles, our heart,
all of that. And we should do this
often. We should do this frequently.
So more than once a week hopefully. So
this is the first reason why you should
do these two things together. Number
one, it's good for your health. And
number two, it helps you find time to
learn English. Okay? If you feel like
you don't have a lot of time in your day
to exercise, to learn English, to spend
time with your family,
then you can combine
two of these things. You can combine
exercise and learning English so that
you have more time to do these things.
So, if you're watching this video right
now, you're practicing English, but you
might not be doing anything else. Maybe
you're just sitting on the couch or
lying on your bed or sitting at a table.
But you can also listen to this video
while you walk, for example. Or maybe
you can go to the gym and use the
bicycle and you can watch this video
while you ride the bike or while you
walk on the treadmill. that machine at
the gym where you walk. You can combine
this practice with some exercise. That's
a good idea. And when you do this, it
can help you with your exercise because
your brain is not only thinking about
the exercise. For example, sometimes
when you run, you're just thinking about
how hard it is, how tired you are, and
so that makes it harder to run. But if
you're concentrated
on an English podcast or an English
video or something like that, your brain
is not only thinking about the exercise
and how hard it is. So that can help you
with your exercise.
And I think that um when you do two
things at the same time like exercise
and language learning and those things
are productive, they're good. You feel
very good about it. You feel productive.
You feel satisfied because you're doing
two things that are good for you at the
same time. I feel great when I uh
practice my languages and exercise at
the same time. It feels fantastic
because I'm saving time. I'm spending
time doing productive things. I'm being
healthy. And it just feels good to do
this. In general, I can't multitask.
Well, I'm very bad at multitasking,
but I can
walk and listen to uh something in
another language or even practice my
speaking,
I can do this. So, if you feel like you
can't multitask, well, you can probably
still combine exercise and language
learning or some types of exercise
maybe. So, if I can do it, you can do
it. And like I said, it feels great. You
will feel good about yourself when you
do this. Okay. Now, let's talk about how
to do this. How can you practice your
English while you're exercising? Well,
maybe the easiest thing to do is
listening practice. You can use YouTube
videos like this or podcasts. And if you
can use your hands, like maybe you're
walking, you can easily rewind, right?
You put the video back 10 seconds or 15
seconds. Uh I do this sometimes. I turn
on the subtitles, the captions for
YouTube videos that I'm using so that if
I'm walking and I hear a word I don't
understand, I can look down and see what
word it is. So, I like to do that. Uh,
and you can also
relisten listen again to things you've
already listened to because maybe you
don't concentrate as much on the video
or the podcast when you're exercising
because you're also exercising.
It's not the same as sitting at a desk
and watching the video. So, because
you're concentrating
a little less, maybe you don't want to
listen to new things. Maybe you can
listen to something you listened to
yesterday and you already know what the
video is about. So it helps you
understand more maybe. So you can do
listening practice. You can also do
speaking practice. I speak to myself
while I'm walking and while I'm hiking.
I speak French to myself out loud if I
can, meaning I say the words uh or in my
head and I use a translator app to
translate words and phrases that I don't
know how to say, uh, but I want to say
them. And when I see a new phrase that I
want to learn, I even create flashc
cards. While I'm walking, while I'm
hiking, I use a flashc card app and make
flashc cards with new words and phrases.
So, I do all of that while I'm walking
or while I'm hiking. I do speaking
practice. I also review flashcards while
I'm walking or sometimes while I'm
hiking. I use the flashcard app and I
review my words and phrases. Of course,
I walk a little more slowly when I do
this. I need to be careful and you
should be careful if you do this. Uh, so
of course using the translator app or
the flashcard app
requires your hands. You need to use
your hands. So, you can't do this for
every exercise. You can't do this if
you're lifting weights unless you take
breaks between uh lifting uh weights and
you use the apps, right? Um so, do what
you can do, but do it safely. Okay? Of
course, if you're walking, you need to
pay attention.
You don't want to fall down. Of course.
So, uh even if you can't use your phone
while you're exercising, you can still
practice your speaking. Um, you can't
look up new words maybe, but you can
still practice talking and that's really
good practice. So, you can do that even
if you can't use your phone while you're
exercising. So, you won't be 100%
focused and concentrated on the English
practice while you're exercising,
but it's still good. You are still being
productive.
You are still learning and practicing.
So, it's a great thing to do. Um, some
people think that they can only learn
English when they're at home and
concentrated
and they have no distractions.
It can be hard to find a lot of time
like that. So I think it's better to use
your time when you exercise
uh to practice English too. Um you
should also u use other time to practice
your English at home uh when you can uh
do it on your computer or in silence.
that's good, too. But why not use your
exercise time to practice more? I think
that's great and that's what I love to
do and I will continue to do. Even this
morning, I practiced French for almost
an hour while walking. I did flashcards.
I spoke French. I translated
things. I listened to French. I did all
of that. And I also walked three miles.
So, uh, I had a productive morning. And
I think that, uh, it's great to do these
things together. So hopefully this video
gave you some ideas on how to exercise
and learn English at the same time. And
hopefully now you can find more time to
practice English and hopefully you
exercise as well. Remember that if you
want my training to help you understand
native speakers when they speak fast or
if you want my pronunciation training so
that you can pronounce things better,
make sure to click on the link down
below in the description and you can get
my training. All right, thank you for
watching this A1 English listening
practice video and I'll talk to you in
the next